Gilang Gumilar

Software Engineer

15339, Jakarta Metropolitan Area, ID

I have more than two years of demonstrated experience working as a software engineer at two unicorn startup companies based in Indonesia. I consider myself to be a life-long learner. I like to code and solve algorithmic problems with it.

SKILLS

Frontend

vue.js | vuex | nuxt.js | reactjs | redux | next.js | node.js | express.js | jest | typescript

Backend

python | java | ruby on rails | sql | django | django rest framework | flask | postgresql

DevOps

docker | kubernetes | aws | terraform | gitlab ci/cd | gcp | kops (kubernetes operations)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer at Traveloka

https://www.traveloka.com/

June 2019- Current

Traveloka is an Indonesian unicorn company that provides airline ticketing, hotel booking services, and lifestyle products. I work as a full-stack engineer building Axes for Biz which is a public self-onboard platform of Traveloka Xperience products.

- Maintain and implement UI forms. (ReactJS, Next.js)
- Improve the landing page performance (Lighthouse audit) by 154%. (ReactJS, Chrome DevTools)
- Design and implement database models and backend services. (PostgreSQL, Java)
- Implement a CI/CD of the static web frontend. (AWS, Terraform, Next.js)

Part-time Frontend Engineer at Bukalapak

March 2018- May 2019

https://www.bukalapak.com/

Bukalapak is an Indonesian unicorn company and one of the leading online marketplaces in Indonesia. I worked as a part-time frontend engineer at Core Frontend team.

- Implemented an internal dashboard of Core Trust and Safety team. (Vue.js, VueX, Vuetify, Express.js)
- Implemented a Vue UI Component Library. (Vue.js, Storybook, Jest, SASS)

Teaching Assistant at Computer Science Faculty of Universitas Indonesia https://www.cs.ui.ac.id/

September 2017- December 2017

VOLUNTEER

Community Contributor at GitLab

March 2020 - Current

GitLab is an open source web-based DevOps lifecycle tool. I contribute to GitLab by fixing and implementing several features.

■ The second most MRs merged (57 MRs merged) of GitLab Hackathon Q2'2020. (Vue.js, Ruby on Rails)

Math Tutor at Computer Science Faculty's Student Council of Universitas Indonesia

April 2016 - May 2016

EDUCATION

LANGUAGES

English

Bachelor Computer Science at Universitas Indonesia

2015 - 2019

Professional working proficiency

Indonesian
Native proficiency

Grade: 3.25